DAYS!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
the State of Qin began its invasion of the State of Wei.
秦国(しんこく)は 魏国(ぎこく)へと侵攻した
The enemy blocking their way is the legendary Great General, Lian Po.
立ちはだかる敵は
伝説の大将軍 廉頗(れんぱ)
Young generals take on this relentless battlefield in hopes of rendering great military achievements.
若き将たちは 大いなる武功を狙い
この苛烈な戦場に挑む
In the first battle on the Liuyin Plain,
流尹(るい)平野での緒戦 蒙驁(もうごう)の中央軍は
Meng Ao's central army fell prey to the machinations of one of Lian Po's Four Heavenly Kings, Xuan Feng.
廉頗四天王のひとり 老獪(ろうかい)な玄峰(げんぽう)の
策に翻弄された
The Feixin Unit and Yufeng Unit launched a lone counterattack, but failed to make a dent in the enemy
唯一 飛信(ひしん)隊と玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊が
反撃に出たが １歩及ばず
中央軍は
大敗を喫してしまったのである
and the Central Army suffered a crushing defeat.
（信(しん)）なっ…
（王賁(おうほん)）ハッ…
We were completely...
俺たちは まんまと…
まんまと
あいつに してやられたんだ！
completely beaten by them!
Shit! Shit!
（信）くそ… くそー！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
このままでは 軍の士気低下は
火を見るよりも明らかだった
It was plain as day that the army's morale would deteriorate given this result...
しかし…
But...
（側近）飛信 玉鳳 両隊は―
The Feixin and Yufeng Units
were undaunted by the enemy's cunning plan
敵の狡猾(こうかつ)な策に対し
１歩も ひるむこともなく
and crushed it with one valorous attack!
勇猛なる攻撃をもって
それを撃破した
As a result, the enemy army has fled
and damage to our army was minimized!
（側近）結果 敵軍は遁走(とんそう)し―
我が軍の被害は
最小限に食い止められた
This can truly be called a victory!
これは
もはや勝利と言って差し支えない！
In order to prevent loss of its morale,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）蒙驁軍は
自軍の士気低下を防ぐため―
信と王賁の２人を祭り上げた
the Meng Ao Army elevated Xin and Wang Ben.
They emphasized and spread the idea that the fact that the two units made the enemy headquarters retreat.
２人の隊が
敵本陣をひかせたことを強調し
吹聴したのである
大敗を知る兵たちも
自らを奮い立たせるべく
The soldiers that knew of the great defeat
joined into that fervor in order to cheer themselves up.
あえて それに乗って 歓声を上げた
クッ… これじゃ逆に さらし者(もん)だ
“敵将逃(のが)したバカ２人”ってな
It's more like we're being publicly shamed.
"Look at those idiots that let the enemy general get away."
Because somebody like you suffered a major wound
お前なんか
更に深手を負わされてっから
二重に恥ずかしいぜ
it's twice as embarrassing.
恥ずかしいのは お前の格好だ
貧乏くさすぎて 皆の士気が下がる
What's embarrassing is your appearance.
You look like such a poor hick that it's going to lower everyone's morale.
What'd you say, asshole?!
…んだと？ てめえ
（王賁）
近づくな　今の俺には加減ができぬ
Don't get close to me. I don't have a lot of patience at the moment.
Would you two cut it out?
（側近）やめんか！ ２人とも
Lord Meng Tian?
（じい）蒙恬(もうてん)さま
（蒙恬）いいんじゃないの？
２人の本陣攻撃がなかったら―
This is okay, isnt it?
If those two didn't attack the headquarters
the damage from the first battle would surely have been much larger...
緒戦の被害は
もっと大きかったはずだし
２人には
ちょっと差をつけられたかな
Looks like those two made some difference.
Though we never got a chance to shine.
まあ
こっちは出番なかったんだけど
（蒙驁）少々わざとらしいが
士気は保たれたゆえ これでよい
It's a bit forced,
but if morale is preserved this way, it's a good thing.
それに わしの２本の剣が動くのは
これからじゃ
Also, my two swords have yet to be unsheathed.
Stay calm... Don't get ahead of yourself, Meng Ao.
慌てるな　せくなよ 蒙驁
The Thief VS The Strategist
On the second day, with the Meng Ao central army having suffered a major defeat in the first battle
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）２日目 蒙驁中央軍は―
緒戦での大敗を受け
各隊の再編制を大急ぎで行っていた
the various units underwent a hurried reorganization.
Get going, Feixin Unit! You're over there!
（将軍）
飛信隊 走れ！ お前らは向こうだ！
I get it! I'm going!
（信）
分かってる　今向かってんだろう！
あっ！ ちゅ… 注目！
A-Attention!
せくな せくな
転んでケガするぞい
Don't rush, don't rush!
You'll hurt yourselves if you trip!
It's General Meng Ao!
（兵士）蒙驁将軍だ！
（兵士）白老さまだ！
The Great White Elder!
The Great White Elder himself came to inspire us!
（兵士）白老さまご本人が
我らに檄(げき)を飛ばしに来られたぞ！
皆に戦術を１つ伝えに来た
I came here to express one strategy to you all.
うん？ 戦術？
Strategy?
Defense!
守備じゃ
Defense?!
（楚水(そすい)）守備？
（蒙驁）戦場の左右に
布陣している副将たちも―
My Vice Generals, who are currently encamped on the right and left sides of the battlefield
まもなく戦いに入る
will be entering the battle momentarily.
両軍は 必ず相対する敵を打ち破り
総本陣まで攻め上がるであろう
Their two armies will without a doubt crush the enemies that oppose them,
and then draw together to form a combined headquarters.
故に その機が来るまで―
Therefore, until that moment comes, us at the center
中央の我々は
ただ ひたすら守りに徹する
must wholly devote ourselves to defense.
If I make it through, our victory will be only a matter of course!
わしを守り抜けば おのずと勝つ！
（蒙驁）そのためには
隊が崩れぬよう 必死で戦え
For that end, I need you all to fight for your lives to keep your units from collapsing.
However, you must be sure to guard your own lives as well.
（蒙驁）ひいては
自分たちの命こそ 絶対に守り抜け
（蒙驁）よいな？ 我が兵たち
Understand, my soldiers?!
我が戦友たち
My comrades in arms, my brothers...
兄弟たち
我が息子たちよ
My sons...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）蒙驁流の檄であった
That was Meng Ao's style of raising excitement.
This un-Supreme-Commander-like way of talking shook the soldiers to the bottom of their hearts.
この大将軍らしからぬ語りかけは
末端の兵士の心まで
熱く震わせたのである
And on this day, the battle began on the wings of the battlefield.
そして この日
戦場の両翼で戦いが始まった
The first ones to move were...
まず最初に動いたのは…
Report!
（魏国伝令）報告！
（伝令）右軍 姜燕(きょうえん)将軍の隊が
General Jiang Yan's unit in the right army
王翦(おうせん)率いる敵左軍と
戦闘に入りました
has entered battle with the enemy left army led by Wang Jian!
（白亀西(はくきさい)）始まったか
So it's begun?!
General Jiang Yan was the one that struck first.
（伝令）先に仕掛けたのは姜燕将軍
State of Wei Army Right Army General
Jiang Yan
State of Qin Left Army General
Wang Jian
Well, the number of soldiers seems even right now.
（廉頗）
まず 兵の数は互角と見ていい
But don't underestimate us, Wang Jian.
だが 王翦よ 侮るな
我が四天王のひとり 姜燕には
恐るべき技がある
Jiang Yan is one of my Four Heavenly Kings. He's got some pretty formidable techniques.
（軍長）谷を下るぞ！
敵の右翼に下から回り込む！
Descend into the valley!
We're cutting into the enemy's right wing from below!
（廉頗）姜燕は 矢で部隊を動かす
Jiang Yan uses arrows to move his unit.
And with marksmanship among the ten best in all of China,
そして
中華で10本の指に入る姜燕の矢は
his range is twice that of a layman.
常人の倍の飛距離を出す
As a result, Jiang Yan can direct every one of his units running between mountains at once.
よって 姜燕は―
山々を挟んで走る各隊を
同時に操ることができるのだ
（兵士）下からも来たぞ！
（兵士）囲まれている！
We're surrounded!
So to start with, they'll be bewildered by the strength of Jiang Yan's attacks.
どの武将も
まずは姜燕の攻めの強さに面食らう
このわしでさえ 昔 幾度となく
あやつの軍に手を焼かされた
Even I had some trouble with that guy a few times way back.
普通ならば このまま押し殺されて
姜燕の餌食になるが
Normally, the enemy would just be crushed to death and become Jiang Yan's prey, but...
I've got a feeling it won't be that easy this time... eh, Wang Jian?
よもや 今回は そうなるまい
のう？ 王翦よ
Why don't you go show me that talent of yours
（廉頗）あの王騎(おうき)が 間違いなく
六大将軍級の武将と評したその実力
that made Wang Qi call you "undoubtedly of the same class as the Six Great Generals".
存分に見せてもらおうか
Urgent report!
（秦国伝令）急報！
王翦軍が押し出され始めました
The Wang Jian Army has started to be pushed back!
敵の攻勢に前線が崩れつつあります
The front line is being broken by the enemy's attack!
（郭叫(かくきょう)）なに？
What?!
General Meng Ao!
蒙驁将軍！
（蒙驁）フォフォフォ…
No need to be concerned, gentlemen. Wang Jian is not someone to be done in so easily.
（蒙驁）皆の者 案ずるな
王翦の実力は こんなものではない
う～む…
Urgent report!
（伝令）急報！
（廉頗）うん？
There has now been movement on General Jie Zifang's front!
（伝令）介子坊(かいしぼう)将軍の前線でも
動きがありました
（廉頗）そっちも動きだしたか
So he's gotten going too, eh?
Our other target... Huan Ji.
もう１人の標的… 桓騎(かんき)
State of Qin Army Right Army General
Huan Ji
State of Wei Army Left Army General
Jie Zifang
（伝令）報告！
第１隊 討たれました
Report!
The first unit has been defeated!
ほかにも多数の被害が…
Others have considerable casualties as well!
（側近Ａ）
なに？ …で 後続部隊は？
What?!
Then what about the next units?!
W-Well, sir, after they slew the first unit,
（伝令）そ… それが
敵は 第１隊を討ったあと―
すぐに退却し 姿をくらましました
the enemy immediately retreated and disappeared.
What?!
（側近Ａ）なんだと？
（介子坊）ンンッ…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）これが桓騎の戦法である
This is Huan Ji's strategy.
つまり 正面から敵に当たらず
山々に分散
Essentially, avoid hitting the enemy head on by dispersing into the mountains
潜伏させた小部隊によって
奇襲攻撃を行うのだ
and then launch ambushes with small concealed units.
Once an attack hits an unguarded enemy, they immediately withdraw.
虚を突いて襲撃しては すぐにひく
これを昼夜を問わず繰り返す
They then repeat this strategy throughout the day and night.
And on occasion when a State of Wei army enters their midst
そして
時折 深入りする魏国軍があれば
待ってましたとばかりに
集団で これを殲滅(せんめつ)した
they attack en masse and annihilate them as if they were waiting for them to arrive.
Jie Zifang wore a brave face as this news came to him,
勇猛をもって
聞こえた介子坊であったが
but this irregular attack frustrated him internally.
この変則的な攻撃には頭を悩ませた
その後 中央軍と王翦軍―
After this, the Central Army and Wang Jian Army
それぞれの戦いは
膠着(こうちゃく)状態となったが
were in a deadlock in each of their battles
桓騎の軍からは
連日 勝利の報告が入っていた
while the Huan Ji Army reported victory multiple days in a row.
そして ４日目
And then, on the fourth day...
Report!
（秦国伝令）報告！
桓騎将軍の隊が またも
敵補給部隊を襲撃いたしました
General Huan Ji's unit
has once again attacked the enemy's supply unit!
That very much sounds like one of General Huan Ji's battles.
（郭叫）誠に桓騎将軍らしい戦い
I can practically see the enemy generals' perplexed faces.
敵将の困り果てた顔が
見えるようです
こういう策では
盗賊の出という過去が生きますなぁ
His origins as a thief really shine through in plans like this.
ハッ… 申し訳ございません
My humblest apologies.
口が滑りました
（蒙驁）よい
A slip of the tongue...
It's all right.
廉頗が このまま 手をこまねいて
見ているわけがない
Lian Po isn't going to just sit back and watch this happen much longer.
He's bound to present some new move soon...
そろそろ新たな動きを見せるころ
じゃが この戦 是が非でも
勝たなくてはならんのじゃ
But we must win this war by any means necessary.
頼んだぞ 桓騎
I'm counting on you, Huan Ji.
（摩論(まろん)）ハハハハッ…
お頭！ 今回も大漁ですぜ！
Boss, we've got a big catch today, too!
（桓騎）フッ…
（魏兵）クッ… お… おのれ
Bastard...
Using nothing buy cowardly tactics... you State of Qin monkeys...
（魏兵）卑怯(ひきょう)なマネばかりしおって
秦国の猿が
Shut your face, worm.
うるせえよ 虫けらが
ハッ… ヒイッ…
（黒桜(こくおう)）フッ…
さ～て…
All right then, I think it's about time we delivered our present...
そろそろ贈り物が届くころかな
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
実は 介子坊を悩ませているのは
奇襲攻撃だけではなかった
It was actually not only the ambushes that made Jie Zifang worried.
It was...
それは…
He-He sent another one?
（側近Ｂ）
ま… また送られてきたのか
その者は？
Who is that?
（魏兵）２日前に
行方が分からなくなっていた―
It's the eighth unit's Thousand-Man General that went missing two days ago.
第８部隊の千人将です
What is in the bags?
（介子坊）袋の中身は？
（魏兵）はっ… これは その…
Well, sir, these are...
Open them for me.
開いて見せよ
（側近Ａ）はっ！
Yes, sir!
It may be best not to.
ここでは やめたほうが…
（側近Ａ）ジャマだ！
Out of my way.
ウワッ！
（魏兵たち）アア…
All of those bags are...
（介子坊）あの袋 全てが…
（伝令）報告！ 再び荷が…
Report!
Another package has...
（側近Ｂ）な… 中身は…
（介子坊）もうよい
T-The contents are...
Enough!
通常 このような非道な行為は
敵の士気を上げてしまうが
Normally terrible acts like this would have the adverse effect of actually raising the enemy's morale,
ヤツのは度を過ぎている
but he is going too far.
If I'm being honest, the fact that he's gone this far
正直 ここまで やられると―
逆に 兵たちの中に
桓騎に対して恐怖心が生まれる
actually has instilled fear towards Huan Ji in some soldiers.
He's a difficult opponent to combat...
やりにくい相手だ
Huan Ji the Beheader.
（介子坊）“首切り桓騎”
Huan Ji
What are you struggling so much with?
（玄峰）何を手こずっておるか
You're the man they call Lian Po's right arm, but...
“廉頗の右腕”といわれた男が
doing such a thing is unworthy of the name head of the Four Heavenly Kings.
四天王筆頭の名が泣くぞ
Lord Xuan Feng!
（介子坊）玄峰さま！
（玄峰）フッ…
（魏兵）玄峰将軍？
（魏兵）玄峰将軍だ！
General Xuan Feng!
玄峰さま　何ゆえ ここへ？
（玄峰）うむ…
Lord Xuan Feng, what are you doing here?
この左軍の実権
しばし わしが預かるぞ
It seems I have been given power over this left army for the time being.
Is this our lord's orders?
殿のご指示ですか？
（玄峰）うむ… まあ 気を落とすな
Well, don't get too down about it.
おぬしの力を疑ってのことではない
He doesn't doubt your ability.
But if this left army is slow going, it will resonate with the entire battle.
ただ ここ左軍がもたつけば
全体の戦いに響く
He wants us to end things quickly and move on to the next move.
“さっさと終わらせて
次に進め”とのこと
But for you, someone whose skill lies in frontal attacks,
じゃが
正攻法を得意とするおぬしと―
that peculiar tactician Huan Ji isn't a good fit.
クセのある桓騎は
相性が悪そうじゃ
I see. So that is why he chose you, Lord Xuan Feng.
なるほど… それで 玄峰さまが
策士には策士というわけですね？
A tactician to match a tactician, yes?
フッ… 一緒にするな
精神攻撃など薄っぺらいわい
Don't lump me with him.
Mental attacks are paper-thin.
I'll teach that man what the weight of a true tactic is.
わしが 本物の軍略の
重さというものを教えてやろう
フッ… まあ こんなもんだろう
Well, that oughta do it.
行くぞ
Let's go.
Tell those guys about this place.
（桓騎）
この場所をヤツらに教えてやれ
（黒桜）あいよ
Aye.
Boss!
（丈虎）お頭！
（桓騎）うん？
（丈虎）敵の本軍が動いたらしい
Apparently the enemy's main army's on the move!
And it looks like where they're going is...
向かっている先は
どうやら 俺たちの本陣だ
our headquarters!
（桓騎）妙だな
That's odd.
I thought the headquarters was hidden in a place where guys like them wouldn't find it.
本陣は あいつらごときには
見つからぬ場所に隠したはずだが
Also, I've got a report from some spies
（丈虎）
それが 間者からも報告があって
どうやら
敵左軍の将が玄峰に代わったらしい
and it turns out they swapped the general of the enemy left army out for Xuan Feng.
The guy that murdered the central army on the first day?
初日に中央軍をやったヤツか
Xuan Feng is the best strategist Lian Po has under him.
（雷土(らいど)）
玄峰は廉頗配下随一の軍略家だ
お頭…
Boss...
（玄峰）
ヤツの作戦には 致命的な穴がある
His plan has a fatal flaw.
With the Huan Ji Army's power dispersed into small units,
（玄峰）
桓騎軍は 軍力を小さく分散し―
they're like flies hovering around the State of Wei Army.
魏国軍の周りを
飛び回っておるハエじゃ
And by sending around corpses and such, he's lowering our morale.
そして 死体を送りつけるなどして
こちらの士気を下げ
Then he combines his units in places where it's particularly low and attacks as a large army.
下げきったところで合体し
大軍で襲ってくる
じゃが 悠長すぎるわ 阿呆(あほう)め
But he's too damn easy-going, that fool.
If his army is dispersed,
（玄峰）軍が散っておるなら
こちらは遠慮なく―
then we don't hold back,
ヤツの本陣を襲撃 壊滅させる
we attack and destroy their headquarters.
その一手で ここの戦は終わりじゃ
With that one move, we'll end the war.
Turning the tables on his plan...
ヤツの策を逆手に…
（側近Ｂ）し… しかし―
B-But Huan Ji's headquarters entered the mountains at the start of the war.
開戦と同時に
桓騎の本陣は山に入り
We haven't heard a thing about it since then.
それ以来 所在が分かっていません
Though we have searched for it.
我々も ずっと捜しているのですが
（玄峰）じゃろうな
Indeed. He is enacting his plan under the supposition that we won't find his headquarters.
ヤツは本陣が見つからぬと想定して
今の作戦を展開している
こういうものは捜しても見つからぬ
But that's not something you'll find by looking for it.
We infer it from the lay of the land, the position of their army, and the direction they are attacking from.
（玄峰）地形と こちらの軍の配置
ヤツらの攻撃している位置から…
Here.
読む！
（玄峰）
ここじゃ　ここに桓騎の本陣がある
This is where Huan Ji's headquarters is.
介子坊　本軍を率いて
ヤツの首を狩ってまいれ
Jie Zifang, lead your main army and hunt down his head.
Yes, sir!
さすがです 玄峰さま
An acute analysis as always, Lord Xuan Feng.
見つけたぞ 桓騎！
I found you, Huan Ji!
Flags - Huan
交戦の構え…
They're in position to resist us.
我らが迫っているのを
察していながら―
I have to give them credit for having the guts to sense us coming, but not run.
逃げなかった度胸は認めてやろう
I will not hold back.
存分に やるぞ！
Everyone, let's go!
皆の者 いくぞ！
（伝令）伝令！
A message!
A report for Lord Xuan Feng!
玄峰さまに報告！
介子坊さま本軍が
敵本陣に襲いかかったもようです
It appears that Lord Jie Zifang's main army has attacked the enemy headquarters!
Oh! Already?!
おお 早くも！
さすが 玄峰さまの読みどおりに
Just as I thought, Lord Xuan Feng's inference was correct.
ならば 終わりじゃ
Then it's over.
剣が交われば ここから桓騎が
こざかしい策を弄してもムダじゃ
No matter what little schemes Huan Ji tries to pull now, it's meaningless.
たとえ ヤツらに
多少の武勇があったとしても
Even if he is a bit brave...
he will not make it past Jie Zifang!
（玄峰）介子坊には通じぬ
オリャー！
何しろ あの男の
敵を破壊する力は 廉頗に匹敵…
In any case, that man's ability to destroy his enemies is on par with Lian Po's...
What?
何じゃ？
Why do you messengers wear armor with blood on it?
（玄峰）
なぜ伝令係のお前たちの甲冑(かっちゅう)に…
血がついておる？
フッ… 目がいいな じじい
You've got some good eyes, old man.
（玄峰）桓騎か
（桓騎）そうだ
Huan Ji?
That's right.
言い残すことはあるか？ じいさん
Any last words, Gramps?
敵兵に扮(ふん)して潜入するなど―
Infiltrating and impersonating enemy soldiers is not something that could be called a war tactic, fool.
軍略と呼べる代物ではないぞ
愚か者が
Much less a general doing it himself.
（玄峰）
まして 将自らやって来るなど
フッ… 軍略？ 知るかよ
War tactic?
I don't give a shit.
I just do whatever makes my opponent angry.
（桓騎）俺は ただ
相手が嫌がることをやるだけだ
（桓騎）
それと 昔から得意なんだよ
And there's one other thing I've been good at for quite a while.
Sneaking in when nobody's home.
留守中に忍び込むのがな
ほう… フッ…
ものを知らぬが
確かに筋は悪くない …か
You may be ignorant,
but you certainly have talent, I suppose.
I wouldn't mind taking you on as a disciple, Huan Ji.
弟子にしてやってもよいぞ 桓騎
要るかよ
Like I want your help,
small fry.
雑魚が
ひくな！
ひかずに今の場所を死守しろ！
Don't retreat!
Protect this place to your dying breath!
信どの！ 聞こえますか？
（信）うん？
Lord Xin! Can you hear that?!
A gong!
ドラの音？
（楚水）はい　恐らくは敵の
Yes.
It's most likely the enemy's...
General, something has happened to the enemy.
（郭叫）
将軍 敵に何かありましたな
うむ…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）それは 魏国軍本陣から
発せられたドラの音による情報が
The information the ringing of that gong signaled from the State of Wei Army headquarters
was delivered to all of the many different battlefields.
それぞれの戦場に
伝えられたものだった
Using that signal, the Lian Po Generals were notified at about the exact same time.
それにより 廉頗の将軍たちに
ほぼ同時に知らされたのである
四天王のひとり 玄峰が
討ち取られたことを
That one of the Four Heavenly Kings, Xuan Feng, had been slain.
I don't believe it... Lord Xuan Feng was killed?!
（輪虎(りんこ)）まさか…
（輪虎）玄峰さまが討たれた？
Lord Xuan Feng was supposed to be at the headquarters. What is it?
玄峰さまは 本陣にいたはずでは…
どういうことだ？
Th... That... can't be...
そ… そんな… バカな…
It appears that Huan Ji disappeared after he slayed Lord Xuan Feng!
（魏国伝令）玄峰さまを
討ち取った桓騎は―
そのまま 姿を
くらましたもようです
なに？ す… すると―
What?!
Th-Then is it possible that Huan Ji is targeting this headquarters?
桓騎は この本陣を
狙っているとも考えられる
ヒイッ！
You've done it now, Huan Ji... State of Qin Army...
やってくれたな 桓騎！ 秦国軍！
L-Let's temporarily retreat the generals and plan a regrouping.
か… 各将を 一度 ひかせて
立て直しを図りましょう
No need!
（廉頗）必要ない
（白亀西）なっ…
The sun will set soon.
じきに日が暮れる
各軍 そのまま野営させよ
Have the various armies make camp where they are.
（白亀西）廉頗将軍！
General Lian Po!
With the loss of Xuan Feng,
（廉頗）玄峰の損失で
少々 戦い方を考えねばならん
I'll have to think a bit about how to fight.
何かあったら 知らせに来い
If anything happens, let me know.
（廉頗）許せ 玄峰…
つまらぬ死に方をさせた
Forgive me, Xuan Feng.
I let you die a boring death...
戦場で生ぬるいことは言えぬが
I can't say anything too soft while I'm on the battlefield,
あれだけ共に
死線を越えてきた うぬを失うとは
but losing you after we faced death together so many times is...
だが 寂しがることはないぞ 玄峰
But there's no reason to feel lonely, Xuan Feng.
すぐに 秦国兵の骸(むくろ)で
そっちをあふれ返してやるからな
Soon that side will be flooded with the corpses of State of Qin soldiers!
これで緒戦の借りは…
Now, the deficit from the first battle has been...
No, I'm a move ahead now, Lian Po.
いや これで
わしが一手 先んじたぞ 廉頗よ
Preview
Meng Tian's Proposal
End